this is such an amazing problem and I
did not expect it to have the outcome
that it had the problem is that we have
a semicircle right here and a quarter
Circle right here and then this red line
with the length of 5 cm which goes from
this vertex and is tangent to this
semicircle we want to find the area of
this rectangle so how can we solve it as
a first step let us assign a radius R to
this semicircle now many of the people
think that this radius is the same as
this quarter circle's radius but it is
nowhere given that they are the same and
in the later steps we will also discover
that we don't require them to be equal
therefore this is one of my favorite
problems so now let us label this radius
as X this piece will also be equal to r
as it is the radius of this semicircle
and this height will be equal to X which
will be the same as the radius of this
quarter Circle we can find the area of
this rectangle in terms of R and X the
base is x + 2 R and the height is X so
the area will be base x height or X plus
2 R * X which will be x² +
2xr now here comes the magic let us draw
a segment from this point of tangency to
the center of the semicircle and this
will be the same as the radius of the
semicircle which is R every radius that
intersects the tangent line at the point
of tangency is at right angle so now we
have a nice right angle triangle and
therefore yes you have guessed it right
we will use Pythagoras Theorem we get r
s + 5² = x +
r² the left hand side will be r² + 25
and the right hand side will be x² + 2xr
+ r² these r s will get cancelled out
and we are left with x² + 2 XR = 25 but
we know that this quantity is the same
as the area of this rectangle so the
area of this rectangle will be 25 don't
forget to put the cm square so good